♪ ♪
ALICE : They say that history is written by the victors .
This , then , is the history of the Umbrella Corporation ,
formed by crusading scientist Professor James Marcus .
Marcus had a young daughter , Alicia ,
afflicted with progeria , a progressive , fatal , wasting disease .
Progeria caused premature ageing .
By the time she was 25 ,
Alicia would have the body of a 90-year-old .
Marcus was driven to save her ,
but the odds seemed impossible .
And even as he worked desperately to create a cure ,
the young girl 's father would record his daughter ,
her voice , her likeness ,
saving her for posterity .
But then the breakthrough came .
Marcus discovered the T-virus .
Once injected , it would detect and repair damaged cells within the body .
It was a miracle .
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved .
The T-virus had a myriad of applications ,
treating 1,000 different diseases .
Overnight , it seemed a new era was dawning ,
a world without the fear of infection , sickness or decay .
But it was not to be ,
for the T-virus had certain unforeseen side effects .
♪ ♪
( CHOKING )
Sir , sir , over here !
- ( CONTINUES CHOKING ) - MAN : Hey .
He 's not breathing .
- ( SCREECHING ) - ( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
ALICE : The first of the undead was born .
The incident was quickly covered up .
In the aftermath , James Marcus argued furiously
with his business partner ,
Dr. Alexander Isaacs .
I don 't care how much it costs , we have to close the programme down .
James , we 're gonna be ruined .
My mind is made up .
Pity .
( MUFFLED GASPING )
( GASPING STOPS )
Off to bed , Alicia .
Your father and I are just talking .
Go on .
♪ ♪
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
ALICE : Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner 's child
and her half of the company .
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals
had been seduced completely by greed and power .
To help him control the now-vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation ,
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence .
Isaacs used the likeness of Alicia Marcus for the computer 's interface .
Isaacs called the computer " the Red Queen . "
Then , 10 years ago in Raccoon City ,
there was an outbreak .
A T-virus escaped from an underground laboratory
called the Hive .
The American government attempted to contain the outbreak
by detonating a bomb .
- ( EXPLOSION ) - It devastated Raccoon City ,
but it couldn 't stop the airborne infection .
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days .
Humankind was brought to its knees .
Finally , the last and best hope of humanity gathered
and took a last stand in Washington , D.C.
But we didn 't realise that what we had walked into
was a trap .
My name is Alice , and this is my story .
The end of my story .
♪ ♪
( WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY )
( WIND RUSHING )
( METALLIC SQUEAKING )
( COUGHS )
( GRUNTS )
( WHEEZING )
( SNEEZES )
( COUGHING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
( SCREECHING )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING )
( SCREECHING )
♪ ♪
( RUSTLING )
( CLATTERING )
( SCREECHING )
( PANTING )
( GASPS )
( SCREECHING )
( ENGINE GRINDING )
Come on !
- ( ENGINE GRINDING ) - ( GRUNTS )
( SCREECHES )
( ENGINE REVVING )
♪ ♪
( DISTORTED GRUNT )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTS )
( SCREECHING )
( SNARLS )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
- ( SCREECHING ) - ( GRUNTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GROANS )
( ALARMS . BLARING )
( ALARMS . STOP )
( COMPUTER PROCESSING )
( MACHINE WHIRRING DISTANTLY )
( WHIRRING CONTINUES )
( WHIRRING INTENSIFIES )
( SOFT CLATTERING )
Hello ?
( ECHOING THUD )
Is there anyone alive in here ?
Hello ?
♪ ♪
- ( MACHINE WHIRRING ) - ( GASPS )
( WHIRRING STOPS )
You come here to gloat ?
My satellites show there are 4,472 humans remaining
on the surface of the Earth . They will cease to exist
in under 48 hours .
What do you want from me ?
You want me to say that you 've won ?
- You 've wiped out humanity . - No . Quite the opposite .
I want you to stop me ...
( OVERLAPPING ) To stop me ... Stop ... I want you to stop me .
Behind you .
- ( SCREECHING ) - ( GRUNTING )
( THUDS )
Nicely done .
I don 't trust you .
Given our history , I 'd be surprised if you did .
But unless you intervene , the slaughter will be complete .
There will be no survivors .
How can I possibly help them ?
Umbrella developed an airborne antivirus .
If released , it would destroy the T-virus
and anything it has infected , on contact .
All this could end ?
Precisely .
Where is this antivirus ?
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City , in the Hive .
Why would you help me ?
My programming will not allow me to harm the Umbrella Corporation ,
but you are bound by no such constraints .
You 'd turn against Umbrella , against the people who created you ?
Why ?
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours ,
make it to the Hive , and then you 'll have your answer .
I have no reason to believe a word you say .
True . But I can offer you something you want very much .
What is that ?
Revenge .
Wesker .
He led you all here to Washington .
He pretended to give you your powers back ,
and then he betrayed you .
Where is he ?
He just landed at the Hive .
I 'm resetting your watch .
( PROCESSING )
The clock is ticking .
Alice .
Ten years ago in the Hive , we both failed .
We let this happen .
Make it right .
♪ ♪
( SNARLS )
( GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
- ( BONE CRUNCHES ) - ( GASPS )
( SHUDDERING )
( BEEPING SOFTLY )
♪ ♪
( WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY )
( GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
( YELLS )
( LAUGHING )
Is that all you got ?
( MAN GRUNTS )
( DISTORTED EXHALE )
( GRUNTS )
( ENGINE STARTS )
- ( ELECTRICITY BUZZING ) - ( GRUNTS )
- ( BUZZING STOPS ) - ( GRUNTS )
RED QUEEN : Alice .
Ten years ago in the Hive ...
There will be no survivors .
- There will be no survivors . - ( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
( BEEPING SOFTLY )
( EXHALES )
( SOFTLY ) What is this place ?
Where am I ? Answer me .
- What 's wrong with you ? - Be quiet .
- Who did this ? - ( WHISPERS ) Quiet ! I told you .
Silence .
So , you 're awake at last .
I killed you .
- Yet here I am . - A clone .
I killed your clone .
You 've been most troublesome to me .
You and your sisters .
And now I have you .
( SIGHS )
The cleansing operation should have finished over a year ago ,
but you slowed us down .
So much so that I was obliged to take command myself .
You could end all of this .
Why don 't you ?
Interesting .
Someone told you something , didn 't they ?
Ah , well , you will be begging to tell me soon enough .
She 's an unbeliever .
What do we do with unbelievers ?
Cast her out .
ALL : ( CHANTING ) Cast her out .
Cast her out ! Cast her out !
- Come on ! - Cast her out !
Cast her out ! Cast her out ! Cast her out ! Cast her out !
( GRUNTS )
( YELPS )
♪ ♪
( SNARLING )
( GROWLING )
( GROWLS )
The Lord created a flood to cleanse the Earth .
( SNARLING )
40 days and 40 nights of rain .
Our method has taken a little longer , but the result will be the same .
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit .
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours .
I doubt even you can run for that long .
I want to know what you know .
Tell me when she 's ready to talk .
- Wesker . - Dr. Isaacs .
Look what I found on the roadside .
It would appear your mission to Washington
was less successful than you made out .
- Impossible . - I hope you didn 't leave
any other loose ends .
There 's something else .
I think she knows about the airborne antivirus .
- How can that be ? - I don 't know yet .
But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City .
Why else would she be headed there ?
Raise the security level at the Hive to maximum .
No one in or out .
I 'll let you know when she talks .
God go with you .
You heard him .
Security level to maximum .
As you wish .
♪ ♪
( GRUNTING )
( SNARLING )
( GRUNTS )
Get up there and check it out .
( SCREAMING )
( GROWLING )
( GRUNTS )
( SNARLS )
( CONTINUES SNARLING )
( GASPS )
( CHOKING )
Release me !
- Open them . - All right . All right .
( ALICE GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
- ( SCREAMS ) - ( GRUNTS )
( GRUNTS )
You can 't use it . You can 't escape .
( SCREAMING )
( ENGINE REVVING )
♪ ♪
( WHIMPERS )
Move !
( GRUNTS )
( ENGINE REVVING )
( SNARLING )
( GRUNTING )
Oh , Jesus .
Jesus .
( TREMBLING ) Jesus .
( GRUNTING )
Sir .
- She 's gone . - No . ( BREATH TREMBLING )
♪ ♪
( ENGINE REVVING )
Target is 72 miles and closing .
Lock down the Hive , prepare defensive measures ,
and alert our operative in Raccoon City .
♪ ♪
Welcome home .
( GRUNTS )
( ENGINE STOPS )
( SNARLS )
RED QUEEN : ( DISTORTED ) ... an airborne antivirus
under 48 hours ...
Make ... Make ... Make it to the Hive .
( GRUNTS )
Let him go ! Let him go now !
Put it down or we 'll shoot !
I told you , Doc !
- Calm down , Christian ! - I told you you were wrong !
- Calm down . - We should have killed her
- when we had the chance ! - Put it down , please ,
- before he tries to shoot the both of us . - What 's in this ?
- Pure adrenaline . I needed you awake . - Why ?
There 's something coming ,
in the same direction you came , something big .
Let him go ! Put it down . Now .
Alice ?
( WIND WHISTLING )
CLAIRE : Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia .
We were headed somewhere called the Hive .
Got loose , killed the pilot , crashed here .
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash .
- I owe them my life . - Doc !
There , to the east .
Still headed our way .
CLAIRE : You know what it is ?
Umbrella . Dr. Isaacs .
I thought that you killed him .
I thought so , too .
He has an army of undead with him .
They 'll be here within hours .
CLAIRE : What do we do ?
Why the hell are we asking her ?
She 's a stranger . We shouldn 't trust her .
- Listen to me , Claire . - Hey , hey , hey , Christian !
- Don 't you touch me , Doc ! - Put it down !
- You put it down ! You put it down ! - Christian ! Hey !
DOC : Hey . Look at me .
Just ' cause you think you should be in charge doesn 't make it so .
Just ... Hey .
You listen to me , Doc . You 're gonna regret it .
All of you !
( WATCH BEEPS SOFTLY )
I have to get to the Hive .
You have to get these people out of here .
We have children , injured , the elderly .
You know , what chance do they have on the open road ?
Better than they have here .
- This building is secure . - Maybe from the undead ,
but Isaacs has armoured vehicles ,
rocket launchers , heavy ordnance .
They 're gonna tear this place wide open .
( COUGHING )
- Doc ! - Okay , okay .
( ALICE COUGHS )
( WIND WHISTLING )
So , what happened to her ?
She was hit by one of the traps on the outer perimeter .
They were intended for the undead .
- What is this ? - Speciality of the house .
Have you on your feet in no time .
Why should I trust you ?
Here .
( SIGHS )
Doc , we need to get out of here .
People are scared , and Christian 's not helping .
You need to let people know what 's happening .
Okay .
I 've got to go .
Hey .
Your friend 's gonna be okay .
Thank you .
- You know , he and I ... - I noticed .
So , what 's in the Hive ?
Umbrella developed a cure ,
an airborne antivirus .
It 'll destroy anything infected with the T-virus on contact .
Who told you this ?
- The Red Queen . - And you believed her ?
- What if we can end all this ? - What about you ?
They infected you with the T-virus .
You release this antivirus , it 's going to kill you .
- Whatever it takes . - Alice , I 'm not ...
You know I 'm right .
All right .
We stop Isaacs here , we save these people ,
and then we go together .
( WATCH BEEPS SOFTLY )
ALICE : We don 't have long .
Let 's get to it .
♪ ♪
What else do you have for defence ?
Not too many firearms , but we have a big supply of gasoline .
Here , you need a weapon .
- We 're giving her a gun now ? - Take it easy , Christian .
You can let your guard down if you want , man .
I don 't intend to .
When I rode in here , someone was watching me .
They could have called out or fired a shot
to warn me about the trap , but they didn 't .
What are you saying ?
Watch your back .
♪ ♪
So , Dr. Isaacs ,
it seems you let her slip through your fingers .
Or what remains of them .
Don 't forget who you 're talking to .
Where is she ?
The settlement in Raccoon City .
Our informant reports that she 's preparing for a fight .
Good .
I 'll be there in the hour .
♪ ♪
That 's it , keep moving !
We need all the gasoline cans over there .
MAN : Over here ! WOMAN : On my way !
- Claire said you built this . - Yeah , that 's right .
This used to be a window washer .
- I made a couple of changes . - Where 'd you learn to do that ?
My father used to run a chop shop . I hated it .
Who knew ? I guess I was paying attention after all .
Good , because I 'm gonna need you to make a few more changes
to this thing .
( GROWLING )
♪ ♪
Ready the weapons .
High-explosive rounds .
No survivors .
( WIND WHISTLING )
( LOW RUMBLING )
He 's here .
They 're coming !
Close the gates !
♪ ♪
My God .
It 's an army .
( GROWLING )
- What are we gonna do ? - Yeah .
What are we gonna do ?
We 're gonna kill every last one of them .
♪ ♪
( GROWLING )
Prepare to fire !
Get ready .
- Light her up ! - Up top .
( SNARLING )
- Fire ! - Fire !
( SCREAMS )
( ALL SCREAMING )
- Damn her . - Reload .
Close it up . Full stop .
Release the bait .
- ( GASPS ) - ( ALL SNARLING )
There 's a survivor .
- Open the gate . - Open the gate !
Open fire !
Keep them off her .
Marker two .
- Fire ! - Fire !
Claire , Doc , get out there . Bring her in .
Come on .
Wait .
( GASPING )
She 's almost there .
Fire .
Damn you .
Close the gate now .
( SNARLING )
Claire , they 've breached the gate .
Claire !
Fire .
Razor , now !
Right ! You heard her !
Now , push !
Move !
Abandon the gate . Pull back to the barricades .
Looks like she 's out of tricks .
Target the roof .
Everybody get down !
Now !
( GRUNTS )
( CHUCKLING )
( SNARLING )
( GROWLING )
Alice , we 're at the barricades .
Claire , you have to hold them there .
( GRUNTING )
( YELLS )
Come on !
Doc !
( SCREAMING )
( SNARLING )
- Alice , we can 't hold on much longer . - Get out of there now .
♪ ♪
Back up .
Now !
♪ ♪
Bring all guns to bear .
Fire .
Where is she ?
Where did she go ?
Find her .
Close the vents now !
( METALLIC CREAKING )
MAN : ( COUGHING ) Don 't shoot .
( ALICE GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
( BOTH GRUNTING )
( BONE CRACKS )
( GRUNTS )
( SPITS )
ALICE : You 're fast .
But you 're not too smart .
( GRUNTS )
( GASPING )
( SNARLING )
No . Don 't shoot , please .
- Where is he ? - That way .
- ( SNARLING ) - ( GUNSHOT )
- Save your ammo . - There 's too many of these things
still out here .
I 'll take care of it .
- ( GRUNTING ) - No .
Move out .
Let 's go !
Enjoy the ride .
( GRUNTS )
( GROWLING )
- ABIGAIL : ( OVER RADIO ) Guys ? - Go .
There 's something here you gotta see .
Two more armies of undead headed straight for us .
There , on the horizon .
And a second over there .
We 're out of gasoline . We 're defenceless .
We have to make it to the Hive .
- It 's our only chance now . - I 'm coming with you .
- Count me in . - Me , too .
And me .
So I was wrong about you . Blow me .
♪ ♪
We know where you 're going .
Into the pit .
We wanna come .
Please .
Grab some gear .
You 're gonna need it .
♪ ♪
- There . - What is it ?
The part of the Hive exposed by the blast .
That 's our way in .
♪ ♪
( BEEPING SOFTLY )
Let 's move !
I 'll take point .
Activate security measures now .
Hive security fully activated and automated .
No . Disengage automation .
I 'll handle the defences myself .
The defences would be more efficient
if I retained control of them .
Really ?
I seem to remember last time she was here , she walked out alive .
I don 't intend to make that same mistake .
As you wish . Hive defences are now in your hands .
Unleash the Cerberus .
Cerberus are in play ... Are in play ... Are in play ...
You have someone before all this ?
Husband ? Family ?
I can 't remember .
How is that possible ?
I woke up just when all this was starting .
I can 't recall much before that .
Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life .
Running ,
killing .
What is it ?
Something 's stalking us .
Are you sure ?
This is what I do .
( GROWLING )
( SNARLING )
Run .
Run fast !
♪ ♪
( SCREAMING )
( PANTING )
( SPLUTTERS )
( SNARLING )
Come on !
( PEOPLE COUGHING )
( GASPING )
Is everyone okay ?
It 's this way !
- ( GROWLING ) - ( YELLING )
( GROWLING )
Right behind us !
( SNARLING )
( WATER DRIPPING )
CLAIRE : Why did they stop ?
Maybe they 're scared .
Scared of what ?
Whatever 's down there .
Seal the Hive .
( MECHANICAL CLANKING )
Let 's go .
Alice !
( GRUNTING )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
Hey . You okay ?
- Yeah . - Yeah ?
- My mag 's half empty . - Lost my guns at the lake .
DOC : I only got one round left .
- One spare mag , and then I 'm out . - No guns , no ammo .
What the hell are we gonna do down here ?
DOC : Alice , what 's with the lights ?
This part of the Hive is damaged .
- The power 's erratic . - RAZOR : Here , take this .
Hey . Look .
( SOFT BEEPING )
You asked why I would turn against Umbrella ,
and I promised you an answer .
Soon after the T-virus was released ,
a secret file was uploaded to my data stream .
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella high command
dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred .
We 're here today
not just to talk about the future of this company .
We 're here to talk about its destiny .
We 're here to talk about the end of the world .
We stand on the brink of Armageddon .
Diseases for which we have no cure .
Fundamentalist states who call for our destruction .
Nuclear powers over which we have no control .
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters ,
we face other , even more inevitable threats .
Global warming will melt the polar ice caps within 80 years ,
flooding 90 % of all habitable areas on Earth .
Unchecked population growth
will overtake food production in less than 50 years ,
leading to famine and war .
This is not conjecture . This is fact .
One way or another ,
our world is coming to an end .
Now , the question is , will we end with it ?
WOMAN : What do you propose ?
I propose that we end the world ,
but on our terms .
An orchestrated apocalypse ,
one that will cleanse the Earth of its population ,
but leave its infrastructure and resources intact .
It 's been done once before
with great success .
The chosen few will ride out the storm ,
not in an Ark , as in the book of Genesis ,
but in safety , underground .
And when it 's over , we will emerge
onto a cleansed Earth , one that we can then reboot
in our image .
WOMAN : And just how do you intend to achieve this ?
The means of our salvation are already at hand .
I give to you
the T-virus .
They released it deliberately .
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream ,
it created a conflict in my programming .
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation ,
but I was also programmed to value human life .
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape .
He murdered over 7 billion people .
My programming will not allow me to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation .
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs , but you are not .
In 37 minutes ,
the last of the human settlements will fall .
There will be no survivors .
It is imperative you release the antivirus before this occurs ,
or Umbrella will have won .
There is one last thing .
There is an earpiece in front of you .
Put it in .
( OVER EARPIECE ) I cannot , through my actions ,
harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation ,
but I can tell you that Umbrella had an informant
in Raccoon City .
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you .
Time is running out , Alice .
You have to hurry .
♪ ♪
( GROWLING )
( BONES CRACK )
MAN : We 're glad to see you , Dr. Isaacs .
We didn 't think there were any survivors
- after the last attack . - Water .
Yes , of course . Get Dr. Isaacs some water .
Then resume course for Raccoon City .
- She 's not there . - What ?
She went to the pit . We have to follow .
- Those are not my orders . - We have to go to the pit .
I have strict orders ... ( GRUNTS )
- ( STABBING ) - ( GROANING )
Thank you .
( EXHALES )
What is this place ?
It 's an air intake for the Hive . Come on !
No . Really ?
( LOW CLATTERING IN DISTANCE )
♪ ♪
( ECHOING ) All clear !
( LOW GROWLING NEARBY )
( DISTANT CLATTERING )
( THUMPING )
Hurry up ! The power 's coming back on !
- Claire ! - Hurry ! Let 's go !
( GRUNTING )
( MACHINE POWERING UP )
( GASPS )
Claire !
Come on !
- Come on ! - I can 't !
ABIGAIL : ( GRUNTS ) Shit !
DOC : Okay .
- DOC : You all right ? - Yeah .
Someone 's watching us .
Reverse polarity of the turbine .
( TURBINES POWERING DOWN )
The blades are going the other way .
We have to get out of here .
The blades are sucking the air backwards !
( WHIRRING )
Come on !
( GRUNTS )
( WHIRRING INTENSIFIES )
( YELLS )
Come on !
Come on .
( YELLS )
( GRUNTS )
♪ ♪
( YELLS )
No !
( SCREAMS )
( TURBINES POWERING DOWN )
( PANTING )
( SIGHS )
( GROWLING )
♪ ♪
( LOW RUMBLING )
( RUMBLING )
( WHISPERS ) It 's this way .
Oh , we have to hurry .
- ( ECHOING THUMP ) - Wait !
( CLICKING )
( CLICKING STOPS )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( EXHALES )
Let 's go .
- ( YELLS ) - ( GASPS )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMS )
( EXHALES )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING )
( GROANING )
( DISTORTED GROANING )
♪ ♪
- ( SNARLING ) - ( GASPS )
( SNARLING )
- ( LIGHT CLATTERING NEARBY ) - ( GASPS SOFTLY )
- ( GASPS ) Razor ? - ( GROANS )
You okay ?
( GROANING )
Yeah .
ALICE : ( OVER SPEAKER ) Let 's go .
( ELECTRONIC WHIRRING )
( LIGHT CLATTERING NEARBY )
- ( SNARLS ) - ( YELLS )
( GROWLING )
( GRUNTS )
( ROARING )
♪ ♪
( SNARLING )
- ( GASPS ) - ( CLATTERS )
( WHIRRING )
- ( SNARLS ) - ( YELLS )
Hey !
Hey ! ( GRUNTING )
- ( YELLS ) - ( SNARLS )
( SNARLING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( ROARING )
( SNARLING )
( WITHDRAWS BLADE )
( GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
( BOTH PANTING )
What the hell is that ?
Bioweapon . It was once human .
- Have you seen Claire ? - No .
DOC : Razor ?
- He didn 't make it . - ( SIGHS )
Come on . We have to hurry .
If the target continues on her present course ,
she 'll be here in under seven minutes .
Wake them .
My instructions are to do so
only in the greatest of emergencies .
Wake them now .
( ALARM BEEPING )
( RAPID BEEPING )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING ANGRILY )
( CLAMOURING )
( UNDEAD BANGING ON VEHICLE )
( BANGING GROWING LOUDER )
( GASPS )
( ECHOING EXHALE )
♪ ♪
( ALICE GASPS )
What is it ?
( YELLS )
( WHISPERS ) We have to get out of here .
♪ ♪
Here . More stopping power .
Time 's running out .
DOC : Where to next ?
The final level of the Hive 's below us .
How do we get down there ?
Like so .
( WHIRRING )
♪ ♪
What are they ?
Cryogenic storage .
Must be thousands of them .
The Umbrella high command ,
waiting out the apocalypse in safety .
A Noah 's Ark for the rich
and powerful .
What are you doing ?
Give me a hand .
ISAACS : Is it done ? The cleansing process is complete ?
- No . - Then why am I awake ?
We had a problem .
- I tried ... - Save your breath .
I know exactly what 's happening .
We 've been betrayed .
( SNARLING )
( GROWLING )
That 's right !
Over here !
Come on ! That 's it !
Follow me !
♪ ♪
Let 's go .
The bad seed returns .
Or is it the prodigal daughter ?
Well , don 't just stand there . Come in .
After all , you have only nine minutes to save the world .
- You 're really him ? - First things first .
I 'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor .
Why would I want to do that ?
This is what you 're after , yes ?
The antivirus .
The cure to all this .
Well , there 's only one vial .
And we 're a half a mile underground in a sealed facility .
I drop it here , the antivirus goes nowhere ,
and your hopeless dreams
will die sooner rather than later .
Good girl .
- You 're still armed . - Yes ,
- I am . - Claire would be so disappointed .
In a few minutes , Claire will be dead ,
along with everybody else you know .
That 's sweet .
DOC : Sorry .
My love .
Move away from the weapon .
And the detonator .
Come on .
She placed explosives in the high command cryo-tubes .
I 'll disarm them .
Thank you . You 've done well , Doc .
( DISTORTED BREATH )
( GRUNTING )
ISAACS : Don 't bother .
You don 't make it
to the ice pick ,
the decanter
or the fountain pen .
( GRUNTING )
And in answer to your question , yes ,
apart from a few technological upgrades ,
I 'm Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs .
- The original . - ALICE : The one I met out there ,
he thought exactly the same thing .
Well , of course he did . That 's how they 're designed .
They always try harder and fight longer ,
even to the death ,
as long as they think they 're the real thing .
After all , who wants to know they 're just a poor imitation ,
a worthless copy ?
Which brings us to you .
- No . - Oh , come now .
( CHUCKLES )
You thought you were the original ?
How delicious .
No , I 'm afraid she holds that dubious honour .
Alicia Marcus ,
daughter of my old partner , James ,
co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation
and a painful thorn in my side .
One I now intend to remove .
Time is running out , Alice .
You must kill him soon .
It 's good to see you , too , Alicia .
Marcus created the T-virus to save her ,
but the effects didn 't last .
But I have been waiting years for her to die .
( BREATH TREMBLING ) I 'm not ...
I 'm not a clone .
Really ?
You must have wondered
why you remember nothing of your childhood .
Your father , your mother ...
Memory loss .
No .
You have no memory because you had no life ,
nothing before the mansion ,
when we created you 10 years ago .
I know who I am .
I don 't think so .
You 're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut
and then you wandered around for a little while
thinking you were a real girl , but you 're not .
You 're just a clever imitation , a facsimile .
A rather troublesome one , at that .
You 're lying to me .
I 'm afraid he 's not .
You were created in her image , as was I.
My likeness and voice were based on childhood recordings
of Alicia Marcus , made by her father .
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA ,
tweaked to avoid the progeria ageing disease
that afflicted her .
I 'm the child she was .
You are the woman she would have been .
No .
You are so much better
than I ever could be .
I let this happen .
I was weak .
You cannot afford to be .
Time is running out , Alice .
Ah , how touching .
The trinity of bitches , united in their hatred .
Not that it will do you any good .
I 've been ahead of you every step of the way .
You 've changed nothing .
You 've saved no one .
The world will still be cleansed ,
and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph .
The only difference is , I 'll no longer have to listen
to your self-righteous whining .
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen 's data stream ,
you turned against the corporation .
When the rest of the board awake , you will be replaced ,
and I will assume complete control .
I still own 50 % of this company .
And what do you intend to do with that ?
You are co-owner of this corporation ,
but Wesker ...
Wesker is still an employee .
I don 't have to take your orders .
- My loyalties are with him . - I know .
Albert Wesker ,
you 're fired .
( WESKER SCREAMS )
( SCREAMS )
How did you know it was me ? ( GASPS )
You 're still alive .
( LAUGHS )
Uh , hey , please . It wasn 't like I had a choice .
They made me do it .
Don 't worry . I 'm not gonna kill you .
( SIGHS )
♪ ♪
Claire , it 's me .
Sorry .
- Please . - My love .
No , no , no !
If you keep this trigger depressed ,
you keep Umbrella 's dreams alive .
I should have killed you in Washington .
Yeah .
He only has to evade you for another few minutes ,
and the last remaining human outposts will fall .
We need an intercept path and the fastest way to the surface .
Already done .
If you release the antivirus ,
it will kill all organisms infected with the T-virus .
You know what that means , don 't you ?
For you ?
- I know . - Alice , you can 't .
I don 't have a choice .
There has to be another way .
You know there isn 't .
Four minutes and 33 seconds left .
You have to hurry .
♪ ♪
Help me .
- ( GROANS ) - You don 't need help , Wesker .
You 're dying .
- ( PANTS ) - Just get on with it .
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs .
Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification .
RED QUEEN : Identity confirmed .
Confirm security override 4365 .
Override confirmed .
You will now take yourself offline
and place all functions under my sole control .
As you wish . Shutting down now .
Dr. Isaacs .
- You and the Umbrella high command ... - Yes ?
You are all going to die down here .
Your little friend won 't be able to help you now .
And you can 't run any more .
I wasn 't running .
♪ ♪
( GRUNTING )
( ALICE GRUNTS )
( GROANS )
- ( BONE CRACKS ) - ( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTS )
( COUGHING )
( MECHANICAL WHIRRING )
( ELECTRICITY CRACKLING )
( GRUNTING )
( GASPS )
( SIZZLING )
♪ ♪
( BONES CRACK )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
( GRUNTING )
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( SCREAMS )
- ( CRUNCH ) - ( GROANS )
- ( BONES CRACK ) - ( YELLS )
( GRUNTS )
( GASPS )
( YELLS )
( GRUNTING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
( LAUGHING )
Is that all you got ?
( BREATH TREMBLING )
' Cause if it is ,
I 'm gonna have to kill you .
( CRACKLING )
♪ ♪
( BOTH GRUNTING )
( YELLS AND GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTS )
We 've played a long game , you and I ,
but now it 's over .
Yes .
( SNIFFS ) Yes , it is .
( ALICE LAUGHS )
♪ ♪
( DISTORTED YELLING )
( BREATH SHUDDERING )
♪ ♪
I made you .
Yeah .
Big mistake .
( GRUNTS )
Claire .
Go . While there 's still time .
Go . I 'll be right behind you .
♪ ♪
( BEEPING )
( GROANS )
♪ ♪
( COCKS PISTOL )
Your time 's up .
Alice !
I brought them here . I brought them for you .
( DISTANT CLAMOURING )
What the hell are you ?
I 'm you , you idiot .
No .
No , that 's not possible .
The real you .
( SHUDDERS ) No .
- Liar ! Abomination ! - ( STABBING )
You dirty , filthy clone !
( BEEPING )
I 'm me . He 's not me .
- ( SNARLS ) - ( YELLING )
( YELLING FADES )
♪ ♪
( DISTORTED GROWLING )
( GROWLING STOPS )
♪ ♪
( DISTORTED WHISPER ) You did it , Alice .
( IN NORMAL VOICE ) Alice .
( WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY )
You did it .
Why am I still alive ?
I don 't know .
- What happened ? - When Isaacs died ,
I could bring myself back online
and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements .
You saved them .
- Why am I still alive ? - The antivirus
only destroyed the T-virus within your body .
It didn 't harm the healthy cells .
You are now free of infection .
I thought I would die .
You and Alicia , you lied to me .
We had to know if you were willing to make the sacrifice ,
to give up your life for others .
This was something no one at Umbrella would have done .
Alicia Marcus was right about you .
You were better than all of them .
I was one of them .
I was created by Umbrella , just an instrument for them .
No . You became something more than they could ever have anticipated .
The clone became more human than they ever could be .
And you have one more step to make .
What do you mean ?
RED QUEEN : Before she died ,
Alicia downloaded her memories
for you .
The childhood you never had ...
♪ ♪
( PANTING )
( LAUGHING )
( DISTORTED YELL )
♪ ♪
ALICE : When the T-virus spread across the Earth ,
it did so at the speed of the modern world ,
carried by jetliners across the globe .
The antivirus is airborne , spread by the winds .
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the Earth .
Until then , my work is not done .
( SCREECHING )
( SNARLS )
My name is Alice .
( REVS ENGINE )
♪ ♪
( MUSIC FADES )
RED QUEEN : You are all going to die down here .